Ihechi Festus

Front End Developer

Frontend developer with around 3 years of experience building scalable, efficient, and maintainable applications from start to finish. I contribute collaboratively in teams and, because of my quick learning ability, I don't hesitate to experiment with new technologies when necessary. I excel in planning and execution, as well as dealing with challenges, and I'm eager to join an agile team that values growth and will challenge me to use my diverse set of skills to achieve the best work possible.

ihechifestus999@gmail.com	+2348132770015
O Jos, Plateau 930222, Nigeria	ihechifestus9.web.app
in https://www.linkedin.com/in/ihechi-festus/	twitter.com/FestusIhechi
github.com/The-Professor99	

SKILLS

Angular	Re	eact	Redux	~	Java:	Script		нтмі	L	Python	ТуреЅсгір	t	CSS	SASS
Bootstra	р	Mate	rialUI	Tail	lwin	dCSS	Je	est	Су	press and	Cucumber	W	ebpack	Figma
Kanban	No	otion	Bash	C	Git	React T	es	ting l	.ibr	агу	Content W	iting	g and Re	search
Flask	Some Cloud Technologies Firebase													

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Frontend Developer

GotRight Technologies

07/2022 - Present

• Assisting in the front end build of websites.

Fullstack Developer, Founder

Syftset Technologies

05/2022 - Present

- A personal project that I started from scratch and have continued to develop till this point.
- Built the frontend of the website using React and some part of the backend using Flask. User authentication, storage, push notifications and analytics were handled using Firebase.
- I had to pick up a lot of skills on the job such as using websockets and flask(for the backend).
- Website link: https://syftset.com
- Project Guide: https://medium.com/@syftset_technologies/cryptocurrency-price-predictions-a-guide-to-using-syftsets-buy-and-sell-signals-e7e820b0cbe8

Career Break

Study Leave

02/2021 - 02/2022

- Took an intentional pause to focus on my final year coursework.
- During this period, I had the opportunity to explore the blockchain(cryptocurrency) industry and also familiarized myself with a few Google Cloud Platform tools, such as Cloud Functions and Cloud Scheduler.
- Graduated and eager to put my newfound skills and knowledge to work.

Freelance Frontend Developer

Unique Help Global Concept Limited

11/2020 – 03/2021 Achievements/Tasks

- I was in charge of the company's website, namely in terms of building the front end **using Angular**, as well as overseeing and managing its progress.
- Working independently with minimal supervision, my duties ranged from designing the website to writing content for it and also bringing the said designs to life through code.
- Worked remotely with a backend developer on the project, through whom I learned a great deal about interacting with the backend through APIs.
- On the job, I had to pick up new skills like using Postman (for API testing) and Google Analytics (to track site engagements), all while meeting deadlines.

Student (Mobile Web Specialist Track)

Google Africa Developer Scholarship

06/2020 – 12/2020 Accomplishment/Tasks

- Skilled up in Mobile Web Specialist skills leveraging expert-authored Pluralsight Content and Program Mentors.
- Assisted in Unblocking stuck members as well as reviewing codes and providing feedback on projects carried out by paired team members.
- I did my fair share of work assigned that saw my team emerge as the best in the Mobile Web Specialist track as well as in the top 3 overall best teams.
- Took very active participation in assigned groups(remote), including setting up alternate methods of group
 interaction to boost engagement when the primary means became weak.
- Worked on assigned projects as well as a capstone project leveraging skills learned over the course of the program.
- Won a badge for a high skill IQ score in the GADS Program.

_I Front End Web Developer (Student Intern)

Nhub Foundation

09/2019 – 02/2020 Tasks

- Actively wrote content for use on projects worked on and assisted with the front end development of these projects.
- Planned and Created Dataflow Diagrams as well as other charts such as Use Case and Entity Relationship Diagrams for the projects undertaken using Lucid Chart.
- Led some teams in pitching projects' goals and projections to stakeholders.

• Worked with team members to build various web-powered initiatives.

• Tutored some of my peers on HTML/CSS and JavaScript.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering(B.Eng)

University of Jos

08/2015 – 11/2021 Study Program

Jos, Nigeria

Electrical and Electronics Engineering.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Built https://syftset.com (05/2022 - present)

- A cryptocurrency price predictions platform built using React for the front end and Flask for the backend.
- The platform also has a social app interface through which users can make posts on topics relating to cryptocurrencies, engage other users' posts, and connect with other users to receive updates on their posts.

Built ecommerce-practice-99.netlify.app/ (03/2022 - 04/2022)

• An Ecommerce practice website I built while learning React.

Built a Face Recognition-based Class Attendance Management Application. (09/2021 – 11/2021)

- Built the application from ground up to completion using Python's machine learning libraries, OpenCV and PyQt6.
- The project can be accessed here (https://pypi.org/project/CAMSyFReT/)

Built a Solar Tracker (Mini Project) (06/2019 – 08/2019)

• A Mini School Project.

CERTIFICATIONS

Certificate of Completion (06/2019 – 08/2019)

Google IT Automation with Python Professional

Certificate - (coursera.com)

Certificate of Completion (06/2019 - 08/2019)

Mobile First Responsive Web Design – (pluralsight.com)

Certificate of Completion (06/2019 - 08/2019)

Angular: Getting Started - (pluralsight.com)

Certificate of Completion (06/2019 - 08/2019)

JavaScript Best Practices – (pluralsight.com)

INTERESTS

Research Writing Machine Lear	rning Blockchain
-------------------------------	------------------